I never thought I'd get through D-day.
Let alone the next phase or the next phase.
I thought I was going to get killed instantly.
I thought one of two things:
A quick death or...
...I'd come through probably without a scratch.
I think everybody had fear.
I think there's people that can handle fear.
I think...
I think I was probably one of them.
I think I was just as...
...scared as anybody else except I could think.
It's a feeling you would not let yourself down...
...and you would not let your comrades or your unit down.
We all had fear.
But we all had training to know that...
...you try to handle your fear...
...and work to accomplish what you're supposed to be doing.
Hey, it looks like what's-his-name.
You know, from 1st Platoon?
Our 1st platoon?
It sure does.
Blithe.
Hey, Blithe.
Blithe!
Thought that was you.
You alone?
You're the first familiar faces I've seen.
I ain't surprised.
They dropped us all over the peninsula.
We've been fighting with the 502nd since we hit the ground.
You?
Oh, I've been...
...trying to find Easy.
Join the club.
Hey, fellows.
Well, look who decided to show up, Floyd.
Hi there, Luz.
We thought we'd never find you guys.
Hey, Tab, get a load of this.
You like that?
It's the real stuff.
Yeah, of course.
You like this?
Oh, nice.
That's a beauty, Sarge.
My Luger's gonna put you all to shame when I get it.
How was your jump?
Missed the DZ.
Yeah, that goes without saying.
I guess so.
Got any souvenirs to trade?
What?
They're all ticking.
Unlike their previous owners.
Got anything good?
Not yet.
Hey.
So, have we lost anybody?
Tommy Burgess took one in the face.
Popeye Wynn got pinked in the behind.
But they're gonna be okay.
That's good.
You run into Lt. Meehan on your travels?
No, why?
Company HQ's still missing.
They think the plane crashed.
They say he's gonna turn up.
Yeah, I ain't holding my breath.
Who's in command, then?
Winters for now.
Lieutenant Welsh is 1st Platoon.
Let's go, 1st Platoon!
Easy's moving out!
On your feet.
Stand up, lift up. Let's go.
Listen up!
It'll be dark soon.
I want light and noise discipline from here on.
No talking, no smoking.
No playing grab-fanny with the man in front of you, Luz.
So, where we headed to, Lieutenant?
We're taking Carentan.
That sounds like fun.
It's the only place where armor from Omaha and Utah Beach...
...can link up and head inland.
Until we take it, they're stuck on the sand.
General Taylor's sending the whole division.
Remember, boys...
...give me three days and three nights of hard fighting...
...and you will be relieved.
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant, I'll take point.
Corporal Hoobler will be lead scout.
Blithe, glad you could join us.
Thank you, sir.
1st Platoon, fall in behind Fox Company.
You people from 2nd and 3rd Platoon, follow us.
Let's shake a leg.
Another thing to remember, boys...
...flies spread disease.
So, keep yours closed.
Don't wake Jerry.
- Damn! - What?
We lost F Company, sir.
Again?
We lost F Company.
Hey, Blithe, Skinny, guess what?
- Perconte, go tell them to hold up. - Yes, sir.
- Hoobler, take Blithe, go find F Company. - Yes, sir.
Come on, Blithe.
Shit.
Did you send somebody?
Hoobler and Blithe are there now.
Why are we stopped?
This is about officers crapping out on their training, Nix.
Come on, let's get this show on the road.
Dang mosquitoes.
What is it?
Shh
Flash.
Thunder.
I can hear y'll all the way across the field.
You F Company?
That's right.
Where you all been?
Blithe, go back to the Lieutenant.
Tell him we've found F Company.
I'll figure out where these yokels are.
Hey, who you all calling a yokel?
He's dead, Private.
Did you find Fox Company?
Yes, sir.
I thought he...
I thought he had me.
Fallschirmjager.
Paratrooper?
We think there's a regiment of them holding Carentan.
Well, there's one less to worry about.
Yeah.
That's edelweiss.
That only grows in the Alps above the tree line...
...which means he climbed up there to get it.
It's supposed to be the mark of a true soldier.
Take the 1st straight up the middle...
...hard and fast.
We must move quickly.
I'll be right behind you with 2nd and 3rd.
Go!
Let's go, 1st, let's go.
Go, go, go!
In the ditch!
Incoming!
God damn it!
Where the fuck is everybody?
Where did everybody go?
I have no idea!
Let's go, Easy!
Get those MGs moving, will you?
Let's get them out of there.
They're in the open, for Pete's sake!
Go, go!
Get going, Buck.
Follow me, Easy!
Move out!
Move out, men!
Go!
Move out, move out!
Get yourselves out of that ditch!
We have men getting killed out there, Blithe!
Move!
Upstairs window, left.
Get yourselves out of those trenches!
Incoming!
That's an MG-42.
There's one in the right upper...
Medic!
Upper flank!
Oh, shit!
Snipers, that way...
...take his lower left.
Ah, shit!
We need some covering fire. Ready, Luz?
Okay, I'm out.
Shit!
Guarnere, clear that sector on the right!
Hit them with me!
You okay, Shifty?
We gotta take that warehouse!
Shifty!
Hammer those windows.
Tipper, take Liebgott, start clearing these buildings.
Right. Let's go!
Second two, go, go!
Houses on the right!
Smash.
Grenade.
Luz, come on, Luz.
Come on.
Close behind.
Shit!
They got us zeroed!
Spread it out, spread it out!
Go!
Get the hell out of there!
They got us zeroed!
Get out of there!
Go, go!
Get the hell out of the street!
Move, now.
Go, go, go!
Come on, let's get you out of here.
Come on, boy.
Move, move, move!
Get off the street!
Go, go!
Move it, now!
Hey, buddy.
You're okay, Lip.
Everything's right where it should be.
Come on, upsy-daisy.
Get Tipper up here with the bazooka.
Hello?
Anybody there?
Tipper!
Tip!
Answer me, Tip!
Joe?
Looking good, Tip.
Is that you?
Looking real good.
Come here, you gotta sit down.
Come here, come on.
Easy, easy.
There you go, there you go.
Ah, Jesus.
You hang in there, buddy.
Okay, we're gonna get you fixed up.
All right? Okay.
Guys, you wanna give me a hand here?
Come on.
Take the left flank!
"In the name of the Father and..."
Hey, Malark.
You see what I'm seeing?
"...is now, and ever shall be, world without end.
"Amen."
Crazy fools, the Irish.
You should know.
Smokey, the window! Let's go!
Morning, sir.
What's your name, trooper?
Sergeant Farmsworth from Able Company 501st.
I'm supposed to tell you...
...it's clear from here north...
...of them Krauts, sir.
Well, tell your CO 506 arrived in force...
...and secured all positions south of you.
Yes, sir, I'll tell him.
Come on, bad boy, let's go!
Lieutenant Winters.
Yes, sir?
Is it safe to cross now?
What's that, sir?
Is it safe to cross?
We wanna move the wounded.
Yes, sir.
Okay.
Come on, let's get them out of here.
There she is.
You're lucky it was a ricochet.
You just caught a piece of it.
Stupid.
What?
Nothing.
Walking wounded to the rear.
Now, you gonna be able to stay off it?
Doesn't look that way.
Well, you gotta try, huh?
What have we got planned, chief?
Well, we expect a counterattack.
Carentan's as important to them as it is to us.
Any idea when?
We're not waiting around to find out.
Battalion wants us to head east to high ground...
...set up a defensive position.
With the flooded fields...
...it's the only direction they'd come from.
Yeah.
You gonna be all right?
Good.
What's wrong with Blithe?
Well, nothing, except he can't see.
He can't see?
So he says.
Blithe?
It's Lieutenant Winters.
What happened?
I don't know, sir.
Things they just kind of went black on me.
You can't see?
Not a thing, sir.
I can't see a thing.
Well, you just take it easy, Blithe.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Get you back to England.
It's gonna be okay.
Sir...
...I didn't wanna let anyone down.
Just take it easy.
It's okay, son.
Sir.
Yeah, what is it?
Thank you, sir.
I'm okay.
Yeah, I'm okay.
I think I'm okay.
You can see?
God, I don't know what happened.
I think, I think I'm okay.
All right.
Well, stay here a little while longer...
...and make sure.
And, then you can report back to your platoon.
Yes, sir.
Now, can we get that bandage on?
Yeah.
Berlin by Christmas.
That's how I see it.
Yeah, you're full of it.
Oh, God.
This Kraut cheese tastes like...
It stinks.
Bread's stale, too.
Give me that.
Yes, sir, the way we came in town today and took over...
...it don't seem Jerry's got much fight left.
More, don't get hit in the face...
...when Jerry throws in the sponge.
You mark my words, Mal, Berlin by Christmas.
Enjoy it while it lasts.
We'll be moving out, soon.
Out of town, Lieutenant? Already?
That's right.
Don't they know we're just getting settled here?
Nice, Groucho.
What?
Real smart.
You know, you're taking your life in your own hands.
Ain't that right?
I told you, I didn't actually see it.
What, his shooting the prisoners...
...or the sergeant in his platoon?
- Sergeant? - I didn't hear that one.
He shot one of his own guys?
Well, supposedly the guy was drunk...
...and refused to go on a patrol.
Who knows if it's true.
Well, I know a guy who said an eyewitness...
...told him that Speirs hosed those prisoners.
Why?
What for?
On D-day.
Speirs comes across this group of Kraut prisoners...
...digging a hole or some such under guard and all.
He breaks out a pack of smokes...
...passes them out.
He even gives them a light.
Then, all of a sudden...
...he swings up his Thompson...
...and he hoses them.
I mean, goddamn, gives them smokes first?
You see, that's why I don't believe he really did it.
You don't believe it?
I heard he didn't do it.
Oh, no, no, it was him all right.
But it was more than eight guys.
It was more like 20.
Hell of a shot.
All except one guy...
...who he left alone.
Well, all I know, from what I heard...
...he took that last 105 on D-day practically by himself.
Running through MG fire like a maniac.
Yeah, that I did see.
- On his own? - Yeah
I don't care if any of the other stuff's true.
Hey, Albert.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I'm gonna have to take everybody's word for it.
I didn't see any of it.
Let's go, 1st Platoon, weapons on me.
We're moving out.
Hey, take all your smokes.
On your feet, tactical column.
Flankers, up.
That means you, Private Blithe.
Come on, Blithe, get up.
Hey, Luz? What?
How far we going?
Oh, Jesus Christ, Frank, I don't know.
Until they tell us to stop.
High ground.
There's high ground up ahead.
Okay, genius, answer me this then:
Why is Easy Company the only company who's either...
...at the front of an advance or, like now...
...exposed at the far edge of the line?
To keep you on your toes.
No, that's not what I'm saying.
I'm saying that we're never in the middle.
And we're the fifth of nine companies of this regiment.
Able through Item.
Think of it.
See there, you see that?
Incoming!
Contact right!
Get in the hedgerow!
See what I mean?
Left, bring it around!
Stay low!
Luz, get down here with the radio now!
What have they got to sing about?
Flash!
Thunder.
Catchy tune...
...ain't it?
Hey, Lieutenant, what's the news?
Oh, same as it was this afternoon.
They're in their hedgerow, we're in ours.
Spell me a minute, sir?
Are you gonna let Blithe get some sack time?
My back teeth are floating.
Get back here ASAP, Martin.
Count on me, sir.
How you doing, Blithe?
I'm okay, sir.
What happened at the aid station today?
Doc Roe...
...called it hysterical blindness.
No, thank you, sir.
You know what they said on basic:
"Dehydration's a soldier's worst enemy."
Yeah.
It's a game, Blithe.
That's all.
Hell, we're just moving the ball forward...
...one yard at a time.
Nothing but a game.
What is, sir?
This. The whole thing.
No.
Thank you, sir.
Just a game.
Harry?
S-2 said the Germans only left a company to defend Carentan.
Yeah. The rest pulled out sometime last night.
I knew that town was too easy.
Yeah.
They regrouped south of town.
May have been on their way to a counterattack...
...when we ran into them here.
Strength unknown.
They want the town back.
And we're in their way.
If they don't come first...
...we're attacking at first light, 0530.
I'll tell the men to fix bayonets.
Not much of a limp.
I'll survive.
How is it?
Hurts.
War is hell.
Smith, wake up.
Come on, Smith.
Get up, it's your watch.
Smith.
It's your watch.
Easy, Smith, it's me, Talbert.
Smith, what the hell are you doing?
That's Talbert.
Goddamn.
Oh, gosh.
Medic!
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to.
He looked like a Kraut.
I didn't know it was him.
You gotta breathe.
Look at me, look at me.
Yeah, I can breathe!
I'll put sulfur on the wound.
You're gonna be fine.
What the hell is that?
Sounds like it's coming from 3rd Platoon.
You wanna get some sleep?
I don't think, I don't think I can.
Then go take a look.
Sarge.
Flash.
Thunder, thunder!
Lieutenant Speirs, sir.
Where are you going, Private?
Check out the noise, sir.
I just came from there.
Everything's under control.
Yes, sir.
Got some nervous privates in your company.
We do, sir.
Yeah, we do, I can vouch for that.
They just don't see how simple it is.
How simple what is, sir?
Just do what you have to do.
Like you did on D-day, sir?
Lieutenant.
Sir, when I landed on D-day...
...I found myself in a ditch all by myself.
I fell asleep.
I think it was those air-sickness pills they gave us.
When I woke up, I didn't really try to find my unit...
...to fight.
I just...
I just kind of stayed put.
What's your name, trooper?
Blithe, sir.
Albert Blithe.
You know why you hid in that ditch, Blithe?
I was scared.
We're all scared.
You hid in that ditch because you think there's still hope.
But, Blithe, the only hope you have is to accept the fact...
...that you're already dead.
And the sooner you accept that...
...the sooner you'll function...
...as a soldier's supposed to function.
Without mercy, without compassion...
...without remorse.
All war depends upon it.
Got any smokes?
Want this candy shit?
No, I'm all right.
The outpost got ammo.
Here you go, guys.
No, we don't know what they've got.
We may be attacking a weaker force...
...possibly more paratroopers.
And you know how they can be.
Fire and maneuver.
That's the name of the game, fire and maneuver.
Dog and Fox Companies will be on our left flank, moving with us.
Any questions?
Let's make them holler.
It's 9:30 in the evening back home.
Must be.
Mortar!
Incoming!
Down, down, down, down!
Get that OP in!
Tell them to hold, I'm checking the lines.
All Easy stations, Easy Six.
Hold in position, over.
Go, lock and load!
Easy Six, Easy Red Six.
I've got mortars all across my line.
No sign of infantry yet.
I'm pulling the OP in, over.
Right plus 15, charge three.
Range, 600.
Come on, move it, move it, hurry!
Watch for silhouettes on the horizon!
Keep low, go, go, go!
Perconte!
Get your men in order!
Stay low!
Pour it at them, Perconte.
To your left.
Keep going, keep going.
Keep it up!
I want fire superiority!
Guarnere, keep them pinned down.
Keep firing!
Sir, just reverse!
Cover the crest of that hill!
Where in the hell did they come from?
Holy shit, there goes our left flank!
Sir, Dog and Fox are pulling back.
What?
Who gave that order, God damn it?
Keep firing, stay low!
Stay low, keep firing, Perconte.
Come on, Blithe!
Stand up!
Get up on your feet, soldier.
Get up, Blithe.
That's right, Blithe.
You can do it!
Fire your weapon, Blithe.
Hit those goddamn Germans, Blithe!
Keep firing!
Let them have it.
Don't slack it off.
Let them have it, Blithe!
Pour it on them, Blithe!
Get some men up there!
Move it!
Let's go, McGrath, on me.
Shift your fire right.
Down, down!
Come on!
You're gonna get me killed, Lieutenant.
I knew you'd get me killed.
Don't fire till I tell you, McGrath.
I knew you were gonna get me killed.
Hold your fire!
No, that's too close!
Bitch, son of a bitch!
Medic!
Go now.
Now, fire, McGrath!
Fire!
Covering fire!
Keep firing south.
You hit a home run, huh?
Smith, I've been hit.
Just get me out of here!
Medic!
You okay?
Move it, move it!
Rounds complete!
Skip, more ammo!
Go, go!
On my way.
Medic!
Jesus, what was that?
Shermans.
Well, hello, 2nd Armored.
That's right, you sorry asses.
Run!
Oh, you beautiful babies, you!
Let's go!
Pour it on them!
Let them have it, come on!
Check it out, Shermans.
About damn time.
Come on!
Come on.
Go to Lt. Kick their ass. Don't let them rest.
Hey, buddy?
Hey, buddy, you okay?
Looks like you fellows had a heck of a fight.
Move forward on the right flank.
We need to know what's in there.
I don't know who the hell to send.
Ask for volunteers.
I hate asking for volunteers.
Then pick them.
Need to take a look at that farmhouse.
Who wants to go?
I'll go.
Anybody else?
Martin, Dukeman, you just volunteered.
Hubba-hubba.
I'll be lead.
Blithe's lead scout, move out.
Harry...
...what exactly are you doing with your reserve chute?
You been hauling that thing around ever since we jumped?
Gonna send it to Kitty when we get back to England.
Silk.
Figure it'll make a good wedding dress, you know?
What with rationing and all.
Jeez, Harry, I never would have guessed.
What?
That I'm so sentimental?
No, that you think we're gonna make it back to England.
Okay.
Here we go again.
Covering fire, covering fire!
Go, go!
Hang in there, Blithe.
Come on.
Keep moving down!
Medic here!
Top window right!
Hang in there.
Medic!
We need a medic down here!
Cease fire, cease fire!
Take it easy, Blithe.
Take it easy.
Come on, Duke, come on.
Move, move.
Coming through, give me room.
Out of my way.
I got it.
What happened?
Sniper.
All right, Blithe, I got you.
Nice and easy, nice and easy.
They're pulling us off the front line.
Now?
To a field camp north of Utah Beach.
Hot food.
And showers.
Then back to England.
Harry.
How's the leg?
Stiff. Sore.
They want me to take it easy for a few days.
Yeah, you should.
Talked to Colonel Sink.
Said he appreciated Easy holding the line.
Said General Taylor was pleased.
That's why I came to France.
To please General Taylor.
Yeah.
In grateful acknowledgement...
...of the bloodshed in service of your country...
...it is my honor to present you...
...with the order of the Purple Heart.
Thank you, sir.
How many's that make?
Two?
Three?
You have no shame.
Hey, I got one hole in my shoulder...
...a second in my calf...
...and a boil on my shin that had to be lanced.
And he only gets one.
This is great.
She fancied me, Alton.
Jesus Christ!
It's good to be alive!
Jesus Christ, that sure was close.
Nah, missed him by a mile.
Hey, Hoobler.
Be quiet for the man.
What?
The Night of the Bayonet.
"The night was filled with dark and cold
"When Sergeant Talbert
"The story's told, pulled on his poncho
"And headed out
"To check the lines dressed like a Kraut"
Why is everyone in such a hurry to get back?
Hospital food don't suit you?
We don't need you anymore.
"Upon a trooper our hero came
"Fast asleep, he called his name
"Oh, Smith
"Get up, it's time
To take your turn out on the line"
Do you guys have any idea what he's talking about?
The Night of the Bayonet.
Whatever that is.
"So very weary
"Cracked an eye, all red and bleary
"Grabbed his rifle, he did not tarry
"Hearing Floyd but seeing Jerry"
Way to go, Smithy.
"'It's me,' cried Tab
"'Don't do it,' and yet Smith charged
"Tout de suite, with bayonet
"He lunged, he thrust, both high and low
"And skewered the boy from Kokomo"
I'm heading back to barracks.
You Heffron?
Yeah.
Where you from?
Who's asking?
You from Philadelphia?
South Philly, yeah.
I could tell.
17th Street.
Front Street.
Hey.
Come here, sit down.
Hey, you know a guy named Johnny Waylon?
Yeah, I know Johnny.
Yeah, tar-head, yeah.
As you weren't wounded by the enemy...
...and thus didn't qualify for a Purple Heart...
...we've taken matters into our own hands.
Tab, this is for you.
That's right.
I could have shot the kid a dozen times.
Yeah, right.
I just didn't think we could spare a man.
Couple of announcements, men.
First, listen up.
First, the training exercise scheduled for 2200 has been cancelled.
Oh, yeah.
Secondly...
...all passes are hereby revoked.
We're heading back to France.
So, pack up all your gear.
We will not be returning to England, boys.
Anyone who has not made out a will...
...go to the supply office.
The trucks depart for Membury at 0700.
As you were.
Hello?
Good morning, Miss Lamb.
Sorry to bother you so early.
That's all right.
Private...
Malarkey.
Come in.
Actually, it's Sergeant Malarkey now, ma'am. I just got promoted.
Oh, lovely.
I expect you want your laundry.
I heard the trucks rumbling by all night.
I guess the Yanks must be on their way off again.
Yes, ma'am.
Looks like for good this time.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Two shirts, two pairs of trousers...
...light starch.
Two bob and tuppence, please.
Thank you.
Would you like a cup of tea?
I've got the water boiling.
No, no, thank you.
I'm in a hell of a...
...bit of a hurry but thank you anyway.
Oh, Private?
Yes, ma'am.
Lieutenant Meehan's one of yours, isn't he?
I hope he hasn't forgotten his laundry.
I'll take it.
Thank you.
You, you couldn't be a dear...
...and help me with a few others, could you?
Let's see.
Sergeant Evans.
Private Moya.
Blowzer.
Gray.
Miller.
Owen.
Collins.
Elliot.
Blithe.